[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：switch语句是Thompson的另一个东西。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The switch statement is another of Thompson's things.
它是仿照托尼·霍尔的案例陈述，或受其启发，
It was modeled after, or inspired by Tony Hoare's case statement,
这是一个绝妙的想法，我们将有几个独立的条款，并且
which was this brilliant idea that we will have several independent clauses, and
我们将根据表达式的值选择其中一个。
we will pick one of them based on the value of an expression.
绝妙的想法，但汤普森以计算Goto的形式重新解释了它，这
Brilliant idea, but Thompson reinterprets it in the form of a computed GOTO, which
是Fortran中的另一个东西，我们后来认定它是个坏主意，除了
is another thing that was in Fortran which we've since decided is a bad idea, except
它以switch语句的形式存在于几乎所有的现代语言中。
it survives in almost all modern languages in the form of the switch statement.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：危险就是落差危险，在任何情况下，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And the hazard is the fallthrough hazard, that in any case,
如果您没有明确中断，它将自动落入下一个案例。
if you do not explicitly disrupt, it will automatically fall into the next case.
在我开发JSLint的早期，有人写信给我，
And early on when I was developing JSLint, someone wrote to me and
建议JSLint对此发出警告，因为这真的很难
recommended that JSLint give warnings on this because it's really difficult
为了查看代码并观察一个案例正在进入另一个案例，
to look at the code and observe that one case is falling through into another,
因为语法的设计是为了掩盖这一事实。
because the syntax is designed to obscure that fact.
我想了很久，我给他写了回信
And I thought about it deeply, and I wrote back to him and
我说，我可以理解这种危险，但有一个很棒的
I said, I can understand that hazard, but there's this wonderful
如果你能让一个箱子掉进下一个箱子，你可以得到优雅。
elegance that you can get if you can cause one case to fall into the next one.
这是一件有价值的事情，错误可能会发生，但它几乎不会发生。
And that's a valuable thing, and the error can happen, but it hardly ever happens.
所以考虑到你有可能发生的好事和不太可能发生的事
And so given you've got this good thing that can happen versus this unlikely
糟糕的是，我不会测试，我不会给它警告。
bad thing, I'm not gonna test for that, I'm not gonna give warnings on it.
我认为这实际上是语言的一个很好的部分。
I think this is actually a good part of the language.
第二天，同一个人写信给我说，我在JSLint中发现了一个bug。
The next day, the same guy wrote to me and said, I found a bug in JSLint.
所以我说，好的，很好，谢谢。
So I said, okay, good, thank you.
我打开调试器，结果是，你知道这是怎么回事，对吧？
I open the debugger and it turns out, you know where this is going, right?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：mm-hm。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Mm-hm.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我有一个案子失败了。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I had a case that was falling through.
在那一刻，我获得了开悟，因为原来我们花了
And in that moment, I achieved enlightenment cuz it turns out we spend
我们大部分时间制造和修复我们自己的错误。
most of our time making and fixing our own bugs.
我们认为，我今天做的事情，我是强力打字。
We think, what I do today, I was power typing.
我在打字。
I was typing.
我们大部分时间都在说，我的上帝，我做了什么？
We spend most of our time saying, my god, what have I done?
然后我们找到了它，我们得到了这种小小的快感。
And then we find it, and we get this little rush of euphoria.
我又做了一次。
I did that again.
砰的一声，我们忘记了。
Boom, and we forget.
所以我们失去了这么多时间。
And so we have all this lost time.
我们忘记了我们在追逐虫子上花了多少时间。
We forget about how much time we spend chasing bugs.
我们没有从错误中吸取教训。
And we fail to learn from our mistakes.
但是在这个特殊的场合，它是如此的羞辱，因为我刚刚给了
But on this particular occasion, it was so humiliating, because I had just given
关于这是一个很好的部分的演讲，然后我看到，由同一个人，
a speech about how this was a good part and then I'm shown, by the same guy,
我自己的代码中的一个bug是由我所捍卫的东西引起的。
a bug in my own code that was caused by that thing that I was defending.
因为太丢人了，我无法避免学到这一课，
And because it was so humiliating, I could not avoid learning the lesson,
也就是说，如果我从来不是故意掉下去的，
which was, if I never intentionally fall through,
我可以找到我不小心跌倒的案例。
I can find the cases where I accidentally fall through.
事实证明这更有价值，这让我重新审视
And that turns out to be much more valuable, and it caused me to re-examine
我的分析，结果证明我在每一个方面都是完全错误的。
my analysis, and it turned out I was completely wrong in every aspect of it.
我以为我在权衡时很合乎逻辑，但我没有。
I thought I was being so logical in measuring the tradeoffs, but I wasn't.
我说过我在为这种美妙的优雅而争辩？
Where I said I was arguing in favor of that wonderful elegance?
不，事实证明这真的是一件坏事，因为它
No, it turns out that's a really bad thing because it
导致这些条款的耦合，这些条款应该是独立的。
causes coupling of these clauses which should be independent.
这意味着代码并不是真的易碎，
And that means that the code is not really brittle,
如果你需要修改一个条款，
that if you need to make a change to one clause,
这将影响其他条款，这些条款现在可能会溢出到其中。
that's going to affect other clauses which can now be spilling into it.
所以你让程序更难维护，你让它更有可能
So you're making the program harder to maintain, you're making it more likely
因为它经过简单的修改，所以引入了bug。
to have bugs introduced to it as a result of its going through simple revisions.
因为我们应该一直在做的就是试图分离事物，对吗？
Because what what we should always be doing is trying to uncouple things, right?
但这会导致隐式耦合，这是不好的。
But this causes an implicit coupling, which is bad.
但更糟糕的是当我说，这几乎不会发生。
But even worse was when I said, that hardly ever happens.
这是另一种说法，对吧。
That's another way of saying it happens, right.
我们不希望它永远发生。
And we don't want it to ever happen.
我们并不是不希望它经常发生，我们希望它永远不会发生，
It's not like we don't want it happen very often, we want it never to happen,
因为我们希望我们的程序是完美的。
because we want our programs to be perfect.
我们不能容忍它出了差错。
We can't tolerate it ever going wrong.
这是系统一号通话。
This is System One talking.
系统一数学很糟糕。
System One is terrible at math.
系统一比所有系统给予更多的重量。
System One gives most more weight than all.
系统一认为零并且不是很多是相同的。
System One thinks zero and not very many are the same.
他们不是。
They're not.
任何时候我们在没有任何数据的情况下进行数学论证，
Any time we're making mathematical arguments without any data,
这可能是系统一的说法，而且很有可能我们错了。
that's probably System One talking, and there's a really good chance we're wrong.
因为它是猜测，它不知道，而我们一直在这样做。
Cuz it's guessing, it doesn't know, and we do this all the time.
所以一个好的风格可以帮助制作出更好的节目。
So a good style can help produce better programs.
风格不应该是关于个人喜好或自我表达或品味。
Style should not be about personal preference or self-expression or taste.
它应该是关于降低你的错误率。
It should be about reducing your error rate.
我们做的每一个关于如何编码这件事的决定，
Every decision we make about how are we gonna code this thing,
我们将如何表达这个东西，它应该是关于我们如何最好地去
how we're gonna express this thing, it should be about how are we best going to
制作一个完美的程序？
make a program which is going to be perfect?
因为归根结底，这就是目标。
Because ultimately, that's the goal.
现在我们可以从文学风格中得到一些关于编程风格的线索。
Now we can get some clues about programming style from the literary style.
罗马人写的拉丁文都是大写的，没有分词或标点符号，而且
The Romans wrote Latin all in uppercase with no word breaks or punctuation, and
对他们有用。
it worked for them.
你可以去罗马，但你仍然可以看到这些字母，我们称之为罗马字母
You can go to Rome and you can still see these letters, we call them Roman letters
今天，因为他们用的就是这个，刻在石头上，看起来就像这样，
today, cuz that's what they used, engraved in stone, looks just like this,
除了他们是用拉丁文写的，但字母是一样的。
except they were writing in Latin, but it's the same letters.
这对他们很管用。
And it worked for them.
他们有一个非常强大的文明，占领了世界的很大一部分，
They had a very powerful civilization that took over a large part of the world,
几个世纪以来。
held it for centuries.
虽然在这方面有不明确的地方，
Although there are ambiguities in this,
例如，我可以将第三行读为，now或db reaks。
for example I can read the third line as, now or db reaks.
这是一种可能的解读，所以这些类型的歧义可能会导致错误。
It's a possible reading, so those sorts of ambiguities can lead to errors.
但在君士坦丁建立基督教之前，它对他们起了很长一段时间的作用
But it worked for them for a long time, until Constantine establishes Christianity
作为罗马帝国的官方宗教。
as the official religion of the Roman Empire.
在这一点上，有必要复制这些文件和
At this point it becomes necessary to make copies of these documents and
把它们分发到世界各地。
distribute them all over the world.
问题是，他们没有这些文件的原件，
And the problem is, they don't have originals for any of those documents,
他们所有的都是复印件。
all they have are copies of copies of copies of copies.
结果发现，没有两个副本是一致的。
And it turns out, no two copies agree.
每次复制它们都会发生变异。
That every time they are copied, they mutate.
如果你试图建立一个派生出
And that's a problem if you're trying to establish an institution that derives
它的权威来自于这个词，没有人能确切地知道这个词是什么。
its authority from the word and nobody can know for certain what the word was.
所以中世纪的模仿者引入了小写，分词，和
So medieval copyists introduce lowercase, word breaks, and
在他们的手稿中加入标点符号。
punctuation into their manuscripts.
而这些创新有助于降低他们的错误率。
And these innovations helped reduce their error rate.
它使复制手稿变得更容易，而不会引入错误。
It made it easier to copy a manuscript without introducing errors into it.
这是一个非常重要的创新。
And that was a really important innovation.
它还出人意料地使手稿更容易阅读。
It also unexpectedly made the manuscripts easier to read.
所以当古腾堡开始用活字印刷时，
So when Gutenberg begins printing with movable type,
他复制了那些惯例，我们还在使用它们。
he copies those conventions and we're still using them.
我们现在有几个世纪使用小写的文学风格的经验，
We now have centuries of experience with literary style using lowercase,
分词和标点符号。
word breaks, and punctuation.
以一种特殊的方式，我们从小就接受过阅读和阅读的训练
In a particular way, we've all been trained since we were children to read and
用那种风格写。
write in that style.
事实证明，这是非常有价值的，你可以很容易地分辨出其中的区别
And that turns out to be really valuable, that you can easily tell the difference
在好的写作和不好的写作之间，它是否符合这一点？
between good writing and bad writing by, does it conform to this or not?
因此，良好的使用风格可以帮助减少错误的发生。
So good use of style can help reduce the occurrence of errors.
我最喜欢的英文风格手册之一是风格元素。
One of my favorite style manuals in English is the Elements of Style.
这是一本小册子，是威廉·斯特伦克自己出版的
It's a little pamphlet that was self published by William Strunk about
100年前
100 years ago.
它已经被EB White和
It's since been updated by EB White and
它需要更新，因为英语从那时起一直在不断发展，但是
it needed to be updated because English has continued to evolve since then, but
斯特伦克的大部分建议仍然很好。
most of Strunk's advice is still really good.
许多计算机科学家将其用作模型
And a number of computer scientists have used it as a model for
写关于编程风格的书非常有效。
writing books on programming style very, very effectively.
所以程序必须清楚地与人沟通。
So programs must communicate clearly to people.
我们应该把我们的节目看作是文学作品。
We should think of our programs as literary works.
而且至少同样重要的是，他们向人们传达他们的所作所为
And it's at least as important that they communicate what they do to people
就像他们对机器做的那样。
as they do to the machine.
写一些真的很草率的东西是不够好的，想着，好吧，
It's not good enough to write something that's really sloppy, thinking that, well,
如果我能让它通过编译器，我已经完成了我的工作。
if I can get it past the compiler, I've done my work.
因为，如果这个程序会被使用不止一次，它将会是
Because, if the program's ever gonna be used more than once, it's gonna to be
对某人来说是必要的，能够理解它并使它变得更好。
necessary for somebody to be able to understand it and make it better.
因此，我们需要让程序传达它们所做的事情，以便允许
And so we need to make the programs communicate what they do in order to allow
我们去做那件事。
us to do that.
否则，我们就是在让自己或他人失败。
Otherwise, we're setting ourselves up or others for failure.